const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"Which of the following structures passes through the diaphragm with the esophagus?","answers":[{"option":"Phrenic nerves","bool":false},{"option":"Right vagus nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Sympathetic trunk","bool":false},{"option":"Thoracic duct","bool":false},{"option":"Azygos vein","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"A patient underwent a chest CT scan that revealed a mass in the anterior mediastinum. Among the following conditions, what is the most likely cause of the mass?","answers":[{"option":"Diaphragmatic hernia","bool":false},{"option":"Thymoma","bool":true},{"option":"Esophageal tear","bool":false},{"option":"Fibroma","bool":false},{"option":"Carcinoma of bronchi","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"A 4-year-old boy was brought to the emergency department. The mother tells that the boy has swallowed a small bead while playing. Which of the following is the most appropriate reason for this bead to enter the right lung?","answers":[{"option":"Right lung has one lobe more than left lung","bool":false},{"option":"Right lung is heavier than the left lung","bool":false},{"option":"Right bronchus is more vertically placed than the left one","bool":true},{"option":"Right lung is shorter than the left lung","bool":false},{"option":"Right bronchus is narrower than the left one","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"While discussing important clinical landmarks, students consider the significant ones in\r\nrelation to the division of mediastinum. Which of the following is primarily considered a landmark to divide the mediastinum?","answers":[{"option":"Foramen of Winslow","bool":false},{"option":"Angle of louis","bool":true},{"option":"Thoracic inlet","bool":false},{"option":"12th thoracic vertebra","bool":false},{"option":"Costodiaphragmatic recess","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"A 60-year-old patient has a profuse amount of fluid in the left pleural cavity due to \r\nacute pleurisy. Where would the fluid accumulate?","answers":[{"option":"Lingula","bool":false},{"option":"Costodiaphragmatic recess","bool":true},{"option":"Hilar reflection","bool":false},{"option":"Costomediastinal recess","bool":false},{"option":"Cupola","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"Which of the following branches of typical intercostal nerves arise near the angle of ribs?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior cutaneous","bool":false},{"option":"Muscular branch","bool":false},{"option":"Rami communicantes","bool":false},{"option":"Collateral","bool":true},{"option":"Lateral cutaneous","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"Which of the following is an incorrect statement regarding posterior intercostal arteries?","answers":[{"option":"Eleven in number on each side","bool":false},{"option":"Content of costal groove","bool":false},{"option":"Give mammary branches to the breast","bool":false},{"option":"Give right bronchial artery","bool":false},{"option":"All are branches of descending thoracic aorta","bool":true}]},{"id":7,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"Which of the following joints of the thorax is a primary cartilaginous joint?","answers":[{"option":"Second sternocostal","bool":false},{"option":"Fourth sternocostal","bool":false},{"option":"Manubriosternal","bool":false},{"option":"Fifth sternocostal","bool":false},{"option":"First sternocostal","bool":true}]},{"id":8,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"Which of the following pairs of ribs is classified as vertebrochondral ribs?","answers":[{"option":"10 and 11","bool":false},{"option":"2 till 7","bool":false},{"option":"1 till 7","bool":false},{"option":"8, 9 and 10","bool":true},{"option":"11 and 12","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"A patient comes to the chest clinic with the complaint of chest pain felt in the ribs. After examination, a diagnosis of pressure on intercostal nerves was made. This compression on intercostal nerves was leading to spasms of the muscles being innervated by these nerves. Which of the following muscles would be unaffected in this scenario?","answers":[{"option":"Innermost intercostal","bool":false},{"option":"Internal intercostal","bool":false},{"option":"Pectoralis major","bool":true},{"option":"Subcostal","bool":false},{"option":"External intercostal","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"In which of the  following weeks do the terminal bronchioles become larger to form two or more respiratory bronchioles\r\nand primordial alveolar ducts are formed?","answers":[{"option":"28 to 32","bool":false},{"option":"11 to 16 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"5 to 10 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"33 to 40","bool":false},{"option":"16 to 25 weeks","bool":true}]},{"id":11,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"Which of the following structures does not participate in forming the thoracoabdominal diaphragm?","answers":[{"option":"Mesentry of oesophagus","bool":false},{"option":"Myoblast from cervical somites","bool":false},{"option":"Pleuropericardial folds","bool":true},{"option":"Septum transversum","bool":false},{"option":"Pleuroperitoneal membrane","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"The trachea is the part of the conducting portion of the respiratory system. The mucosa is lined by pseudostratified ciliated columnar epithelium. Glands in the submucosa cartilage and adventitia. Which of the following structures has the same\r\nhistological appearance as the trachea?","answers":[{"option":"Respiratory bronchioles","bool":false},{"option":"Terminal bronchioles","bool":false},{"option":"Intrapulmonary bronchus","bool":false},{"option":"Pre-terminal bronchioles","bool":false},{"option":"Extrapulmonary bronchus","bool":true}]},{"id":13,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"During chest auscultation, a physician instructs his patient to inhale deeply. Which of the following muscles are accountable for facilitating this ventilation procedure?","answers":[{"option":"Scalenes and internal intercostals","bool":false},{"option":"Diaphragm and internal intercostal muscles","bool":false},{"option":"Diaphragm and external intercostal muscles","bool":true},{"option":"Rectus abdominus and internal intercostals","bool":false},{"option":"Internal and external intercostal muscles","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"A 50-year-old smoker is diagnosed with restrictive lung disease, which affects his\r\nlung tissue's ability to expand. Which of the following is most likely to be reduced in this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Tidal volume","bool":false},{"option":"Inspiratory reserve volume","bool":false},{"option":"Vital capacity","bool":false},{"option":"Expiratory reserve volume","bool":false},{"option":"Residual volume","bool":true}]},{"id":15,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"A person is hiking at a high altitude mountain, where the air has a lower oxygen concentration. As a result, they experience changes in their respiratory rate and depth to adapt to the lower oxygen levels. Which of the following physiological mechanisms primarily regulates respiration in this situation?","answers":[{"option":"The somatic nervous system","bool":false},{"option":"Central chemoreceptors in the medulla oblongata","bool":true},{"option":"The stretch receptors in the lungs","bool":false},{"option":"Peripheral chemoreceptors in the carotid bodies","bool":false},{"option":"The Hering-Breuer reflex","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"Which of the following effects on the respiratory system occurs due to parasympathetic stimulation?","answers":[{"option":"Bronchoconstriction via nicotinic receptors","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchoconstriction via alpha 1 receptors","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchoconstriction via muscarinic receptors","bool":true},{"option":"Bronchodilation due to acetylcholine receptor activation","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchodilation via beta 2 receptors","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"In a healthy individual which one of the following is the primary regulating variable of central chemoreceptors?","answers":[{"option":"Arterial pH","bool":false},{"option":"Input from irritant receptors","bool":false},{"option":"PaO2","bool":false},{"option":"Input from stretch receptors","bool":false},{"option":"PaCO2","bool":true}]},{"id":18,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"An 80-year-old obese person has been diagnosed with sleep apnea, a condition\r\nwhere he experiences repeated pauses in breathing during sleep. This is primarily\r\ndue to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Overactive diaphragm muscles","bool":false},{"option":"An increase in blood oxygen levels","bool":false},{"option":"A decrease in lung compliance","bool":false},{"option":"Relaxation of pharyngeal muscles","bool":true},{"option":"A decrease in carbon dioxide levels","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"Repaying the oxygen debt after exercise is primarily achieved to regulate which of the following processes?","answers":[{"option":"Elevate body temperature","bool":false},{"option":"Oxygen bound with myoglobin only","bool":false},{"option":"Reconvert phosphocreatine to creatinine and phosphate","bool":false},{"option":"Reconvert ATP and ADP to AMP","bool":false},{"option":"Reconvert the lactic acid back into glucose","bool":true}]},{"id":20,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"A 20-year-old patient with asthma is prescribed an inhaler that contains a bronchodilator. Which receptors are inhibited by the bronchodilator to help alleviate her asthma symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Beta-1 adrenergic","bool":false},{"option":"Beta-3 adrenergic","bool":false},{"option":"Beta-2 adrenergic","bool":false},{"option":"Nicotinic","bool":false},{"option":"Muscarinic","bool":true}]},{"id":21,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"Following a road traffic accident, a 25-year-old young man experiences breathing difficulties. Upon arrival at the emergency department, a lung function test was conducted, revealing a reduction in his functional residual capacity. What does this reduced capacity signify?","answers":[{"option":"The volume of air that lingers in the lung after a normal exhalation","bool":true},{"option":"The volume of air expelled after a standard exhalation","bool":false},{"option":"The sum of inspiratory reserve volume and tidal volume","bool":false},{"option":"The volume of air inhaled and exhaled during a typical breath","bool":false},{"option":"The volume of air that stays in the lung after a complete exhalation","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"A 20-year-old male presents to the emergency department with a fractured rib. The patient experiences painful breathing and thus takes rapid, shallow breaths. His respiratory rate is 40 breaths per minute with a tidal volume of 200 ml. What would be his alveolar ventilation rate?","answers":[{"option":"6000 ml/min","bool":false},{"option":"2000 ml/min","bool":true},{"option":"400 ml/min","bool":false},{"option":"200 ml/min","bool":false},{"option":"4600 ml/min","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"A patient with a history of chronic lung disease is experiencing decreased lung compliance. What is the primary factor contributing to this reduction in lung compliance?","answers":[{"option":"Reduced alveolar surface area","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased thoracic cage flexibility","bool":false},{"option":"Increased elastic recoil of the lungs","bool":true},{"option":"Decreased surfactant production","bool":false},{"option":"Elevated intrapleural pressure","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"In which of the following conditions is cyanosis absent?","answers":[{"option":"High altitude pulmonary edema","bool":false},{"option":"Impaired gas exchange secondary to pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary embolism leading to V/Q mismatch","bool":false},{"option":"Right to left shunt in congenital heart disease","bool":false},{"option":"Aplastic anemia with 4g/dl Hb","bool":true}]},{"id":25,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"A 45-year-old male received a penetrating stab wound on the chest wall resulting in intrapleural pressure becoming equal to atmospheric pressure. This change in the pressure would cause which one of the following effects on the lung?","answers":[{"option":"Reduced work of breathing","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased airway resistance","bool":false},{"option":"Increased surfactant","bool":false},{"option":"Increased compliance","bool":false},{"option":"Collapse of alveoli","bool":true}]},{"id":26,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"A 70-year-old male who has smoked 50 cigarettes per day for 45 years complains of shortness of breath and is diagnosed with chronic emphysema. Which of the following changes are present in this patient with respect to lung compliance, lung elastic recoil, and total lung capacity as compared to a healthy non-smoker?","answers":[{"option":"Decreased, decreased, decreased","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased, decreased, increased","bool":false},{"option":"Increased, decreased, increased","bool":true},{"option":"Increased, decreased, decreased","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased, increased, increased","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"A 60-year-old male suffered a stroke that resulted in damage to an area that controls forced expiration during rest and exercise. Which one of the following was most likely affected in this individual?","answers":[{"option":"Pneumotaxic center","bool":false},{"option":"Ventral respiratory group","bool":true},{"option":"Pre-Botzinger complex","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal respiratory group","bool":false},{"option":"Apneustic center","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"A healthy 25-year-old woman reports coughing paroxysms when the temperature goes below freezing. Which of the following sensory receptors may have triggered this response?","answers":[{"option":"Pulmonary stretch receptors","bool":false},{"option":"Central chemoreceptors","bool":false},{"option":"Juxtapulmonary capillary receptors","bool":false},{"option":"Peripheral chemoreceptors","bool":false},{"option":"Irritant receptors","bool":true}]},{"id":29,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"During strenuous exercise, an athlete's alveolar ventilation increases to 6 L per minute while pulmonary blood flow rises to 7.5 L per minute. Which one of the following V/Q ratios is present at this moment?","answers":[{"option":"1.2","bool":false},{"option":"0.5","bool":false},{"option":"0.6","bool":false},{"option":"0.8","bool":true},{"option":"0.7","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"Which one of the following factors keeps the pulmonary alveoli dry under normal conditions?","answers":[{"option":"High capillary hydrostatic pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Negative interstitial fluid pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Reduced pulmonary lymph flow","bool":false},{"option":"Phagocytic activity of alveolar macrophages","bool":false},{"option":"Low vapor pressure of water in inspired air","bool":true}]},{"id":31,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"A patient has an episode of hematemesis (bloody vomiting). His Hb level is 11 gm/dl before the event of hematemesis. He is treated in a hospital. After 1 day, CBC report shows a Hb level of 10gm/dl. At this level of Hb, what is the oxygen-carrying capacity of his blood?","answers":[{"option":"12.4","bool":false},{"option":"14.6","bool":false},{"option":"10.2","bool":false},{"option":"11.8","bool":false},{"option":"13.4","bool":true}]},{"id":32,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"Which of the following conditions leads to stagnant hypoxia?","answers":[{"option":"Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease","bool":false},{"option":"Iron deficiency state","bool":false},{"option":"Shock and heart failure","bool":true},{"option":"Cyanide poisoning","bool":false},{"option":"CO poisoning","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"A 45-year-old man has been experiencing chronic hypertension with muscle weakness and frequent muscle cramps despite lifestyle modifications and antihypertensive medications. On investigations, he is diagnosed with Conn's\r\nsyndrome (primary hyperaldosteronism). Which of the following biochemical characteristics is possible in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Decrease in the ratio of HCO3: H2CO3","bool":false},{"option":"Disproportionate decrease in HCO3-","bool":false},{"option":"Decrease in PCO2","bool":true},{"option":"Increase in total CO content","bool":false},{"option":"Decrease in H2CO3","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"A 47-year-old female presented to the emergency with a severe asthma attack, sweating, shortness of breath, fatigue, headache, drowsiness, and confusion. On examination, she is found hyperventilating, Her arterial blood gases report showed pH = 7.20, PaCO₂ = 58 mmHg, and HCO₃⁻ = 21 mEq/L. What is the provisional diagnosis of this patient based on ABGs?","answers":[{"option":"Respiratory acidosis","bool":true},{"option":"Respiratory alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Mixed acidosis/alkalosis","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"A 1-day-old preterm neonate presented with complaints of tachypnea (Increased respiratory rate), respiratory distress, and cyanosis. A history of gestational diabetes mellitus was present in the mother. Which of the following is most likely\r\nfinding if the amniotic fluid was assessed after 34 weeks of gestation?","answers":[{"option":"Lecithin/sphingomyelin ratio of more than 2","bool":true},{"option":"Lecithin/sphingomyelin ratio of less than 1","bool":false},{"option":"Lecithin/sphingomyelin ratio of less than 5","bool":false},{"option":"Lecithin/sphingomyelin ratio of more than 5","bool":false},{"option":"Lecithin/sphingomyelin ratio of less than 2","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"\"The enzyme responsible for the breakdown of phospholipids into fatty acids and glycerol\". The given explanation best corresponds to which of the following enzymes?","answers":[{"option":"Amylase","bool":false},{"option":"Phosphorylase","bool":false},{"option":"Phosphatidyl kinase","bool":false},{"option":"Phosphatidyl phosphorylase","bool":false},{"option":"Lipase","bool":true}]},{"id":37,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"Slow-reacting substances of anaphylaxis (SRS-A) are an important regulator in many diseases involving inflammatory or immediate hypersensitivity reactions such as asthma. Which of the following explanations best corresponds to slow-reacting substances of anaphylaxis?","answers":[{"option":"Anti-inflammatory compound","bool":false},{"option":"Mixture of leukotrienes C4, E4, and D4","bool":true},{"option":"Cyclooxygenase pathway product","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibited by NSAIDs","bool":false},{"option":"Vasodilator","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"Bicarbonate buffer is an effective physiological extracellular buffer comprising carbonic acid (the proton donor) and bicarbonate (the proton acceptor). Which of the following statements about bicarbonate and its effectiveness as a buffer is accurate?","answers":[{"option":"The bicarbonate buffer is most effective at a pH of 7.0, maintaining a neutral environment in the body","bool":false},{"option":"The bicarbonate buffer is most effective at a pH of 6.1, corresponding to the pKa of carbonic acid","bool":true},{"option":"Decreased activity of carbonic anhydrase leads to increased plasma bicarbonate concentration","bool":false},{"option":"Carbonic anhydrase is the primary enzyme that catalyzes the formation of CO2 in the bicarbonate buffer system","bool":false},{"option":"A fall in physiological pH is associated with a state of primary bicarbonate deficit due to decreased plasma bicarbonate concentration","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"The presence of which of the following is the main difference between glycerophosphatides and phosphosphingoside?","answers":[{"option":"Plasmalogens","bool":false},{"option":"Lecithin","bool":false},{"option":"Phosphatides","bool":false},{"option":"Sphingosine","bool":true},{"option":"Lipositol","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"A 32-year-old man is found unresponsive on the street and brought to the emergency department. Emergency personnel found what is presumed to be heroin and a syringe near his body. He is lethargic and cyanotic with symmetric pinpoint pupils. Vital signs are temperature 36.0°C (96.8°F); heart rate 70/min; respiratory rate 6/min; and blood pressure 100/60 mmHg. An arterial blood gas sample (ABG) is drawn in addition to the following laboratory tests:\r\nSerum Na+ = 138 mEq/L\r\nSerum Cl- = 101 mEq/L.\r\nSerum K+ = 4.0 mEq/L\r\nSerum creatinine (SCr) = 0.58 mg/dl.\r\n\r\nWhat would most likely be seen on this patient's ABG?","answers":[{"option":"Normal pH; increased PCO2; increased HCO3-","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased pH; decreased PCO2; decreased HCO3-","bool":false},{"option":"Increased pH; decreased PCO2; decreased HCO3-","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased pH; increased PCO2; increased HCO3-","bool":true},{"option":"Increased pH; increased PCO2; increased HCO3-","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"A 35-year-old man has chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) and has elevated levels of carbon dioxide in his blood, resulting in respiratory acidosis. How would his body attempt to compensate for this respiratory acidosis?","answers":[{"option":"The bicarbonate buffer system releases more bicarbonate ions","bool":true},{"option":"The respiratory rate increases to expel more carbon dioxide","bool":false},{"option":"Patient's blood becomes more alkaline","bool":false},{"option":"The kidneys excrete excess bicarbonate ions","bool":false},{"option":"The kidneys will absorb H+ ions","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"Which of the following is the least characteristic of asthma?","answers":[{"option":"Infiltration of eosinophils in the airway","bool":false},{"option":"Mast cell activation and degranulation","bool":false},{"option":"Airway hyperresponsiveness","bool":false},{"option":"Increased mucus production","bool":false},{"option":"Increase in IgG immunoglobulins","bool":true}]},{"id":43,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"Which of the following congenital diseases affecting the lungs is most common?","answers":[{"option":"Congenital diaphragmatic hernia","bool":false},{"option":"Pleural effusion","bool":false},{"option":"Marfan's disease","bool":false},{"option":"Lack of pulmonary surfactant protein B","bool":false},{"option":"Tracheo-oesophageal fistula","bool":true}]},{"id":44,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"A 50-year-old man (a known patient with rhinitis and polyps) presents to your clinic with a history of repeated asthma attacks and urticaria. On further inquiry, she reports taking aspirin for her lower back pain. What is the most likely cause of her asthma attacks?","answers":[{"option":"Aspirin damages her distal airways causing them to dilate","bool":false},{"option":"Polyps in her nose also cause her to have polyps in her lungs","bool":false},{"option":"She most likely has a positive family history for asthma","bool":false},{"option":"Aspirin causes increased leukotrienes production which causes bronchospasm","bool":true},{"option":"Nasal polyps and rhinitis predispose her to necrotizing bronchial infections","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"Asthma is a common obstructive lung disease. It is characterized by which of the following pathological changes?","answers":[{"option":"Airway dilatation and scarring","bool":false},{"option":"Necrotizing inflammation and fibrosis of airway walls","bool":false},{"option":"Smooth muscle hyperplasia, excess mucus and inflammation","bool":true},{"option":"Airspace enlargement and wall destruction with no obvious fibrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Inflammatory scarring and obliteration","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"Which of the following statement is correct about the lung diseases?","answers":[{"option":"Restrictive lung diseases are characterized by reduced expansion of the lung","bool":false},{"option":"Obstructive lung diseases are characterized by limitation to air flow","bool":true},{"option":"Obstructive lung diseases are characterized by reduced expansion of the lung","bool":false},{"option":"Restrictive lung diseases are characterized by limitation to air flow","bool":false},{"option":"Restrictive lung diseases are characterized by reduced expiratory flow rate","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"Which of the following is the most appropriate regarding community-acquired pneumonia?","answers":[{"option":"It mostly presents like bronchopneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Risk factors include <5 and >65 age","bool":true},{"option":"The most frequently identified organisms are gram-negative","bool":false},{"option":"Symptoms always include hemoptysis","bool":false},{"option":"Symptoms always include pleurisy","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"A 75-year-old man has been hospitalized for the past 1 week with COVID-19 pneumonia. He develops sudden onset dyspnea and tachypnea. His lips appear blue and his oxygen saturation drops drastically. Chest x-ray shows diffuse bilateral infiltrates (white lung). What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Miliary tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Fat embolism","bool":false},{"option":"Acute on chronic bronchitis","bool":false},{"option":"Acute respiratory distress syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Septicemia","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"A 22-year-old female presents with a persistent cough, low-grade fever, and unintentional weight loss of 5 for the past three months. She reports occasional night sweats and a family history of TB. On physical examination, lymph nodes are palpable and there are decreased breath sounds over the right upper lung field. A chest X-ray reveals a cavitary lesion in the right upper lobe. A fine needle aspiration is performed on the lymph nodes and pus is aspirated. What is the underlying process behind this pus formation?","answers":[{"option":"Caseous necrosis","bool":true},{"option":"Fibrinoid necrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Coagulative necrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Liquefactive necrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Apoptosis","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"A 35-year-old male presents with a persistent cough, low-grade fever, and night sweats for the past two months. He reports a history of working in a homeless shelter. Physical examination is unremarkable except for mild cervical lymphadenopathy. A chest X-ray shows infiltrates in the right upper lobe. Acid-fast staining of sputum confirms the presence of acid-fast bacilli. Which of the following mechanisms best explains the early events in the infection?","answers":[{"option":"Formation of abscesses in lung tissue","bool":false},{"option":"Production of exotoxins causing tissue damage","bool":false},{"option":"Intracellular survival within alveolar macrophages","bool":true},{"option":"Invasion and replication within RBCs","bool":false},{"option":"Development of encapsulated cysts in lung parenchyma","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"A 28-year-old healthcare worker, recently exposed to a patient with confirmed\r\n pulmonary tuberculosis, is concerned about possible infection. She undergoes a Mantoux tuberculin skin test. Two days later, the test site revealed a 12 mm induration. What mechanism best explains the positive result of the Mantoux test?","answers":[{"option":"Delayed-type hypersensitivity reaction to tuberculin","bool":true},{"option":"Direct activation of mycobacterial antigens in the skin","bool":false},{"option":"Activation of B cells and antibody production against TB","bool":false},{"option":"Activation of neutrophils and tissue destruction","bool":false},{"option":"Immediate hypersensitivity to purified protein derivative (PPD)","bool":false}]},{"id":52,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"A 6-week-old infant presents with severe paroxysms of coughing and whooping sounds, along with posttussive emesis. The patient has not received any vaccinations yet. Bordetella pertussis infection is suspected and the patient is treated with antibiotics. Pertussis toxin, a known virulence factor of Bordetella Pertussis plays a crucial role in the pathogenesis of the disease. What is the mechanism of action of this toxin?","answers":[{"option":"Inhibition of neutrophil chemotaxis to the site of infection","bool":false},{"option":"Induction of toxin-neutralizing antibodies","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibition of bacterial adhesion to respiratory epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"ADP-ribosylation of G proteins, leading to increased cAMP production","bool":true},{"option":"Blockade of histamine release from mast cells","bool":false}]},{"id":53,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"A 37-year-old male with a history of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease presents with high fever, cough, and confusion. He is admitted to the hospital and a chest X-ray reveals multifocal, patchy consolidation. A diagnosis of atypical pneumonia is made. On probing, he provides a history of attending a meeting during the last week. Which of the following is the most likely cause of his illness?","answers":[{"option":"Klebsiella pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Legionella pneumophilia","bool":true},{"option":"Pseudomonas aeriguinosa","bool":false}]},{"id":54,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"A previously healthy 12-month-old child presents with fever, cough, and increased respiratory effort. A chest X-ray reveals a right lower lobe consolidation with pleural effusion. Sputum culture grows gram-negative coccobacillary rods on chocolate agar. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Actinobacter","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudomonas aeruginosa","bool":false},{"option":"Hemophilus influenzae","bool":true},{"option":"Legionella pneumophilia","bool":false},{"option":"Klebsiella pneumonia","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"A 40-year-old male, obese, smoker underwent surgery for a femur fracture. He stayed in the hospital for one week and was on anticoagulant therapy. At home, he suddenly developed dyspnea and cyanosis. He was taken to the hospital but could not survive. Which risk factor is least likely to be associated with his cause of death?","answers":[{"option":"Immobility","bool":false},{"option":"Recent surgery","bool":false},{"option":"Obesity","bool":false},{"option":"Age","bool":false},{"option":"Smoking","bool":true}]},{"id":56,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"A 35-year-old male with a severe, persistent cough, and expectoration of foul-smelling sputum, particularly frequent when the patient rises in the morning. He also has a history of chronic sinusitis. On chest X-ray, bronchi are dilated, bronchovascular markings are increased, pulmonary vasculature appears ill-defined, representing fibrosis. What are the conditions that predispose to this disease?","answers":[{"option":"Smoking","bool":false},{"option":"Congenital alpha-1 anti trypsin deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Atopic individual","bool":false},{"option":"Kartagener's syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Obesity","bool":false}]},{"id":57,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"Which one of the following is a feature of Kartagener syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Emphysema","bool":false},{"option":"Autosomal dominant","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchospasm","bool":false},{"option":"Cor pulmonale","bool":true},{"option":"Atypical metaplasia","bool":false}]},{"id":58,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"Due to its anti-inflammatory mechanism of action, which of the following medications require regular administration for the treatment of asthma?","answers":[{"option":"Tiotropium","bool":false},{"option":"Beclomethasone","bool":true},{"option":"Salmoterol","bool":false},{"option":"Albuterol","bool":false},{"option":"Salbutamol","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"Oral medications are popular for the treatment of asthma in children because young children may have difficulty with the proper use of aerosol inhalers. Which of the following is an orally active inhibitor of 5-lipoxygenase enzyme to inhibit leukotrienes?","answers":[{"option":"Zileuton","bool":true},{"option":"Aminophylline","bool":false},{"option":"Ipratropium","bool":false},{"option":"Albuterol","bool":false},{"option":"Montelukast","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"A patient is advised to take antitubercular therapy for six months. After 12 weeks of treatment, the patient complains of visual defects. Which drug is responsible for this side effect?","answers":[{"option":"Pyrizinamide","bool":false},{"option":"Streptomycin","bool":false},{"option":"Rifampin","bool":false},{"option":"Isoniazid","bool":false},{"option":"Ethambutol","bool":true}]},{"id":61,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"A 49-year-old cobbler contracts severe diarrhea due to cholera. He used to drink and eat from the roadside hotels. He has a low BMI with a history of hypertension, and his personal hygiene is poor. He lives in a small space with many other workers. In the above scenario, what is the primary determinant of his acute illness?","answers":[{"option":"Poor nutrition","bool":false},{"option":"Diabetes","bool":false},{"option":"Bacteria","bool":false},{"option":"Personal hygiene","bool":false},{"option":"Poverty","bool":true}]},{"id":62,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"A young mother was informed by the birth attendant that her recently born firstborn baby has trisomy 21. The reason for the above-mentioned disease lies at what stage?","answers":[{"option":"First hour after birth","bool":false},{"option":"Organ development","bool":false},{"option":"Placenta development","bool":false},{"option":"Just before the childbirth","bool":false},{"option":"Fertilization","bool":true}]},{"id":63,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"A type of learning in which a neutral stimulus is presented repeatedly with one that reflexively elicits a particular response so that the neutral stimulus eventually elicits the response itself is known as classical conditioning. After a certain time, the response becomes extinct but it can re-emerge after a period of time has passed with no further conditioning. What is the name for this phenomenon?","answers":[{"option":"Operant conditioning","bool":false},{"option":"Learning","bool":false},{"option":"Stimulus generalization","bool":false},{"option":"Extinction","bool":false},{"option":"Spontaneous recovery","bool":true}]},{"id":64,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"Sarah is in a bad mood and forcefully smiles for 10 seconds. This behavior can be explained by the facial feedback hypothesis. Which of the following does this hypothesis suggest?","answers":[{"option":"None of the above","bool":false},{"option":"Once we know how we are feeling, we can change our facial expression","bool":false},{"option":"Some people disguise their emotions if they look in a mirror","bool":false},{"option":"The movement of our facial muscles can trigger emotions","bool":true},{"option":"We can judge someone else's mood by looking at their face","bool":false}]},{"id":65,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"The pulmonary function test of a 40-year-old male showed the following values:\r\nFEV1/FVC- 65% of predicted\r\nTLC- Normal\r\nFVC- Normal\r\nDLCO- Low\r\nWhat would be the most likely diagnosis from this PFT?","answers":[{"option":"Sarcoidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Emphysema","bool":true},{"option":"Chronic bronchitis","bool":false},{"option":"Interstitial lung disease","bool":false},{"option":"Asthma","bool":false}]},{"id":66,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"A 13-year-old female presents to the outpatient department with complaints of off-and-on shortness of breath for the last few years, especially during winters along with whistling sounds. Which of the following findings on the chest examination would be the most appropriate?","answers":[{"option":"Barrel shaped chest on infection","bool":false},{"option":"Increased percussion note","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased chest expansion","bool":false},{"option":"Bilateral wheezes on auscultation","bool":true},{"option":"Bronchial breath sounds on examination","bool":false}]},{"id":67,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"Which one of the following is an example of a post-contrast CT chest?","answers":[{"option":"Post-traumatic patient","bool":false},{"option":"Suspected covid pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Staging of cancer","bool":true},{"option":"Interstitial lung disease","bool":false},{"option":"Biopsy of lung/pleural mass","bool":false}]},{"id":68,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"Which of the following is considered a first-line treatment for the treatment of acute asthma exacerbations?","answers":[{"option":"Oral antihistamines","bool":false},{"option":"Inhaled long-acting beta-agonists","bool":false},{"option":"Inhaled short-acting beta-agonists","bool":true},{"option":"Inhaled corticosteroids","bool":false},{"option":"Leukotriene receptor antagonists","bool":false}]},{"id":69,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"In addition to oxygen saturation, which of the following parameters should be closely monitored in a patient with acute asthma exacerbation to assess disease severity?","answers":[{"option":"Total IgE","bool":false},{"option":"Forced expiratory volume in one second (FEV1)","bool":false},{"option":"Serum pro-inflammatory cytokines","bool":false},{"option":"Fractional exhaled nitric oxide (FeNO)","bool":false},{"option":"Peak expiratory flow rate (PEFR)","bool":true}]},{"id":70,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"What is a common trigger for acute asthma exacerbation?","answers":[{"option":"Bacterial infections","bool":true},{"option":"Smoking cessation","bool":false},{"option":"High humidity","bool":false},{"option":"Inhaled corticosteroids","bool":false},{"option":"Emotional stress","bool":false}]},{"id":71,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"Pulmonary surfactant is essential for life as it lines the alveoli to lower surface\r\ntension, thereby preventing atelectasis during breathing. Surfactant is enriched\r\nwith a relatively unique phospholipid. What is this unique phospholipid termed as?","answers":[{"option":"Cardiolipin","bool":false},{"option":"Triacylglycerol","bool":false},{"option":"Ceramide","bool":false},{"option":"Dipalmitoylphosphatidylcholine","bool":true},{"option":"Monopalmitoylphosphatdylethanolamine","bool":false}]},{"id":72,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"If the partial pressure of (PCO2) increases in a patient due to airway obstruction, what will happen to the oxygen dissociation curve?","answers":[{"option":"Shift down","bool":false},{"option":"Remain the same","bool":false},{"option":"Shift up","bool":false},{"option":"Shift to left","bool":false},{"option":"Shift to right","bool":true}]},{"id":73,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2023","question":"Which of the following correctly represents the oxygen dissociation curve?","answers":[{"option":"Linear","bool":false},{"option":"Sigmoidal","bool":true},{"option":"Parabolic","bool":false},{"option":"Wavy","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperbolic","bool":false}]}]
export default arr